JOSHUA MORGAN

Greenville, SC 29650

FULL STACK DEVELOPER - React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB

864-404-1515

Linkedin | GitHub

joshuamorgan0605@gmail.com

Summary

I am a **full stack developer** specializing in **React**, **Node.js** (**Express.js**), **MongoDB**, and **Jest**. My current interests include **Next.js**, **TypeScript**, **Cypress.io**, **React Testing Library**, and **Storybook**. I have **3 years** of experience in the JavaScript ecosystem. And I have built and worked on web applications geared toward the general public and general industry.

Projects

React Job Simulator (<a>Code | <a>View Site)

December 2023 - March 2024

Took part in job simulation program designed by Sr. React developed. Worked on error logging and monitoring tool built with **Next.js** framework, **React**, and **TypeScript**.

- Completed feature requests from **Kanban board** simulating professional work environment.
- Wrote automated tests with **Cypress**, improving proper project design and function.
- Built UI kit based on **Figma** designs, creating pixel-perfect rendering.

In-Season Produce Project (<u>Code</u> | <u>View Site</u>)

May 2023 - November 2023

A full stack **Node.js (Express), React** application for the person seeking to find in-season local produce.

- Developed **RESTful API** using **Express.js**, with **MongoDB** as a persistence layer, utilizing **React**.
- Incorporated **React Router v6** for client-side routing, providing faster user experiences.
- Incorporated **JWT Web Tokens** and **HTTP Cookies**, securing the transfer and storage of sensitive data.

Experience

Berkshire Hathaway

2017 - 2019

Licensed Real Estate Agent – Summerville, SC

• Supported buyers and sellers in process of purchasing or selling residential property.

Spartanburg Day School

2013 - 2016

Upper School VISTAS Teacher – Spartanburg, SC

• Supported learning disabled students (ADHD, Aspergers, Dyslexia, etc) in acquiring and applying the skills and know-how to succeed in a college-preparatory classroom, improving letter grades and confidence.

Hanalani Schools 2010 – 2011

Upper School Instructor — Mililani Town, HI

• Built 10th grade English curriculum that conveyed core content while also inspiring collaboration, adaptive problem-solving skills, critical thinking, communication, and positive digital citizenship.

Evangelical Christian School

2007 - 2009

Upper School Instructor — Fort Myers, FL

- Tailored Theology curriculum, giving students a personal and appropriate learning experience.
- Develop curriculum for Keyboarding class, leaving students with a comprehensive and interactive course.

Education

Full Stack Software Engineering

June 2020 - Feb 2023

Launch School — (Link)

Elementary Teacher Certification

Aug 2011 — May 2012

USC Upstate. — Spartanburg, SC

Masters of Arts in Teaching

Jan 2004 — May 2007

Bob Jones University — Greenville, SC